Preliminary Guide to the Collection of Twentieth-Century Graphic Art
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Twentieth-Century Graphic Art
1900-1999
AOB 76
Yale University Arts Library
1
(3 boxes + 1 broadside drawer)
This collection contains examples of graphic art from 1900-1999. Many of these materials are not dated; an educated guess as to the age of the material was based on paper type and subject matter.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Collection of Twentieth-Century Graphic Art was housed in the former Arts of the Book Collection until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains examples of graphic art from 1900-1999. Many of these materials are not dated; an educated guess as to the age of the material was based on paper type and subject matter.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Posters. II. Prints. III. Maps & Diagrams. IV. Reproductions of Artwork. V. Miscellaneous.
Posters -- 20th Century -- Specimens.; Graphic arts; Serigraphy -- Specimens.; Intaglio printing -- Specimens.; Prints; Relief prints; Intaglio prints; Woodcuts (prints); Posters
- Posters, Series I
  - American
    - Exhibition posters, 1966-1989; 36 (Box 1)
    - Exhibition posters, 8 items (Box Broadside drawer)
    - Books, Bookselling, & Book culture, circa 1980 undated; 9 (Box 1)
    - Books & Bookselling, 1 item (Box Broadside drawer)
      - Dover Publications, circa 1980; 19 (Box Broadside drawer)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 4 (Box Broadside drawer)
    - Miscellaneous, 1901 1979-1984 undated; 14 (Box 1)
    - Hollywood fashion, circa 1930 (Box Broadside drawer)
    - World's Fair, 1939; 5 (Box 1)
    - Food & laundry, circa 1930; 9 (Box 1)
  - Brazilian - exhibition poster, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - British - exhibition poster, 2 (Box 1)
  - Dutch - exhibition poster, 1981 1986; 2 (Box 1)
  - French
    - Exhibition posters, 1945-1956; 7 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - German, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 2 (Box Broadside drawer)
    - Books & Bookselling, undated (Box 1)
    - Exhibition posters, 1973 undated; 5 (Box 1)
  - Italian, 1 (Box Broadside drawer)
  - Russian, 1 (Box Broadside drawer)
  - Swiss, 1 (Box Broadside drawer)
- Prints, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Relief printing includes a set of woodcut prints by Gustave Baumann. Intaglio printing includes a suite of works by Maxwell Simpson and images from the Society of Iconophiles, circa 1920.
  - Relief Printing
    - Silkscreen, 1963-1978 undated; 19 (Box 2)
    - Silkscreen, 1967 1970 undated; 4 (Box Broadside drawer)
    - Wood or linocut, 1954 undated; 5 (Box Broadside drawer)
    - Wood or linocut, 35 (Box 2)
  - Intaglio Printing, circa 1920-1980; 48 (Box 2)
    - Portraits, circa 1910; 4 (Box Broadside drawer)
  - Unknown, 1 (Box Broadside drawer)
  - Planographic, 38 (Box 2)
- Maps & Diagrams, Series III
  - Various maps and diagrams, 1929 1976 1982 undated (Box 1)
- Reproductions of Artwork, Series IV
  Arrangement
  Categories are based on the country or region of origin for the artwork, not the publisher.
  Of particular note is a large-scale foldout of the Column of Trajan (located in Broadside drawer).
  - American, 15 (Box 1)
  - Asian, undated; 38 (Box 1)
  - European, undated; 33 (Box 1)
  - South American, 1 (Box 1)
  - Unknown, 18 (Box 1)
  - Various origins, undated; 23 (Box Broadside drawer)
- Miscellaneous, Series V
  - Miscellaneous artwork, undated; 13 (Box 1)